天呐  是兰斯·德鲁卡
Oh, my god. It's Lance Delorca.
是嘛
Really?
这是90年代的潮流
This was in fashion in the '90s?
是啊  我以前在学校穿这个搭马腾博士靴可帅了
Yeah, I used to rock that in school with my Doc Martens.
你知道我们家什么锅都有吧
You do realize we have a full range of all-clad at home.
但这个我最喜欢了
Except this one's my favorite.
我小时候  我奶奶用这个
My nona used to make me scrambled eggs in it
-给我做炒蛋  -懂了
- when I was little. - Gotcha.
我就把其他的厨房用具留给我亲戚索菲娅
Okay, so, I'm gonna leave the rest of this kitchen stuff here
搬进来后用了
for when my cousin Sofia moves in.
我觉得我不会怀念这里的
You know, I don't think I'm gonna miss this place.
-什么意思  -地板咯吱响
- What do you mean? - Well, the floors creak,
隔壁库比亚克先生在厕所做什么我们都听得到
and we can hear everything Mr. Kubiak does in his bathroom.
你以前没说过啊
You never said anything about it before.
现在都无所谓了啊  你要搬走了
It doesn't matter now. You're moving out.
谢谢
Thanks.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯  没事
Yeah, sure. I'm fine.
死者可不是"没事"
Which can't be said for our dead guy.
引座员昨晚11点半左右闭店
Usher was closing up last night around 11:30,
看到有人逃离现场
saw someone fleeing the scene.
然后发现了尸体
That's when he found the body.
他说那人的长相了吗
Did he say what that someone looked like?
只说穿了深色外衣
Just a figure in a dark coat.
至于被害人
As far as our vic goes,
没有钱包  身份证  手机
there's no wallet, no I.D., no cell.
但引座员认为他可能是...
But the usher thinks that he might be...
兰斯·德鲁卡
Lance Delorca.
那是谁
Who's Lance Delorca?
那个人啊
He's that guy!
他是80年代的动作电影大明星
He's one of the biggest action heroes of the 1980s
是我年轻时的好榜样
and a huge role model from my youth.
好吧  他是有点眼熟
Okay, well, - he does look a little familiar.
有点  他是《铁胆硬汉》系列电影的主角
"A little"? He's the star of all the "Hard Kill" movies.
前海豹特遣队队员  禅宗瑞克·克鲁斯
Ex-navy seal, zen master Rico Cruz
他的经典口头禅  "该克鲁斯控制局面了"
with the catchphrase "Time to hit Cruz control"?
嗯  我一向不喜欢他
Yeah, I was never a fan.
我也是  他最近都拍过什么
Me, neither. What's he done lately, anyway?
-是啊  -抗击白血病
- Yeah, right? - Beat leukemia.
他多年没拍戏了
Yeah, he hadn't acted in years.
由于吸毒  酗酒
Suffered a couple setbacks
和票房失利  他屡受打击
due to drugs, alcohol, and some box-office flops.
但兰斯住在洛杉矶
But... but Lance lived in l.A.
不知道他怎么跑这儿来了
I wonder what he was doing in town.
还出现在这家剧院
And at this theater.
他来看自己的老电影吗
Did he come here - to watch one of his own movies?
引座员说没有
The usher said no.
而且尸体上也没有票根
And there was no ticket stub found on the body.
他身体和手上都有生前留下的瘀伤
There is perimortem bruising on his hands and torso.
卡塞尔的偶像肯定跟人打架了
Castle's idol must have gotten into a fight
就在死前不久
not too long before he died.
死因显然是勒毙
Cause of death is clearly strangulation by ligature.
看来凶器很窄
A narrow ligature, from the looks of it.
是绑在两根木钉上的细线留下的吗
Made by a thin wire tied to two wooden dowels?
鉴证组在垃圾桶里找到的
C.S.U. found this in the dumpster.
绞喉  谁会用这东西啊
A garrote. Who would use one of those?
特种部队想安静杀人时会用
Special forces will sometimes when you want to kill quietly.
更大的问题是
Well, the bigger question is
凶手怎么能制住兰斯·德鲁卡
how'd they get the drop on Lance Delorca?
兰斯扮演动作片英雄  卡塞尔
Uh, Lance played an action hero, Castle.
他本人并不一定是好身手
It doesn't mean he was one.
恰恰相反  我的朋友
Au contraire, mon frere.
兰斯是西班牙人  他成为动作明星前
Lance was born in Spain, where, before he became an actor,
曾是西班牙情报机构西情局特工
he was a member of the CNI, the spanish intelligence agency.
负责秘密行动  此人是致命武器
He was black ops. This man was a lethal weapon.
嗯  看来还不够致命
Yeah, well, not lethal enough.
让鉴证组查凶器找指纹
Have C.S.U. take a look at the murder weapon for prints.
我去找亲属
I'll get ahold of his next of kin.
看看他们是否有什么头绪
We'll see if they know who might have done this to him.
每个人都有价码  大佬
Every man has his price, El Jéfe.
说出你的  我们了结此事
Name yours, and we can end this.
看啊
There he is...
兰斯·德鲁卡饰演瑞克·克鲁斯与
Lance Delorca as Rico Cruz squaring off with El Jéfe,
亨利·布斯饰演的残忍毒枭大佬对峙
the ruthless drug lord, played by Henry Boothe.
这场戏里  大佬从卡塔赫纳一挖掘现场
See, in this scene, El Jéfe has just abducted
绑架了一位天才又丰腴的考古学家
a brilliant but buxom archaeologist from a dig in Cartagena.
现在  瑞克想付赎金解救她
Now Rico is trying to pay him ransom to get her released.
-这游戏很危险  先生  -我在你身后
- ...Dangerous game, senor. - "I got your zero."
我在你身后  瑞克
I got your zero, Rico.
需要支援  说一声就好
"You need backup, just say the word."
You need backup, just say the word.
我把他们都干掉
And I'll take 'em all out.
我是单亲妈妈养大的
I was raised by a single mother.
《铁胆硬汉》就是我的爷们时光了
"Hard kill" was how I got my bro time.
这解释了好多事情啊
That explains so much.
那是瑞克所有《铁胆硬汉》电影里的搭档
That's Rico's partner in all the "Hard kill" movies,
布克·戴恩  布鲁克·哈蒙饰演
Booker Dane, played by Brock Harmon.
嗯  《不倒硬汉》系列里的那家伙
Yeah, the guy from - "The indestructibles" movies,
集结了所有动作片硬汉
where all the badass action heroes
-一起执行最后一起任务  -趁他们还有气
- band together for one last mission. - Before they die of old age.
那电影很棒  续集也很棒
Hey. It's a great film. And so is the sequel.
大佬的女手下  布鲁克妻子饰演的
El Jéfe's henchwoman, played by Brock's wife,
娜奥米·杜瓦雷  黑衣的
Naomi Duvray, the one in the black.
-别碰我  -闭嘴
- Get your hands off me. - Shut up!
她来了  克鲁斯先生
There she is, Mr. Cruz.
-你的宝贝考古学家  -那个红发女
- Your precious archaeologist. - The redhead?
她是考古学家  这太不科学了
She's an archaeologist? That strains credibility.
是啊  但是效果很赞
Yeah, in a good way.
都忙着调查呢
Hard at work investigating, I see.
其实  我刚联系了交管局
Uh, actually, I just called TSA,
兰斯是两周前来这儿的
and Lance flew into town two weeks ago.
我们还在查他落脚在哪
We're still trying to run down where he was staying.
我让鉴证组查了那个绞喉
And I had C.S.U. take a look at that garrote.
上面没有指纹或DNA
There's no prints or DNA,
但绞喉线是高强度单纤维丝
but it's made out of a high-strength monofilament.
而我  找到了亲属
And I... Found the next of kin.
-那个考古学家  -是啊  兰斯跟她结婚了
- The archaeologist? - Yeah. Lance married the actress.
她叫凯特·金斯利
Her name's Kat Kingsley.
我知道
I know what her name is.
你们在这儿开B级电影节时
While you were having your B-movie festival,
我找到了她
I tracked her down.
她就在纽约  在拍电影
She's in New York, she's shooting a film,
她正在赶来
and she's on her way in now.
她要过来
She's coming here?!
我在墙上挂过她的海报  挂了...
I had her poster on my wall for like...
没多久
...for about a minute.
你这次还是别参与了  卡塞尔
You know, maybe you should sit this one out, Castle.
感觉好不真实  简直...
This doesn't seem real, like it's just a...
像场噩梦
a bad dream.
金斯利女士  你知道有谁
Ms. Kingsley, do you know of anyone
会想伤害你丈夫吗
that would have wanted to harm your husband?
没有
No. Of course not.
你最后跟他通话是什么时候
And when was the last time you talked to him?
一周前
It was a week ago.
-我们想一起吃饭  最终没吃成  -一周
- We tried to meet for lunch, but it never worked out. - A week ago?
你们俩没住一起吗
The two of you weren't staying together?
我们在离婚
We were getting a divorce.
我陪伴兰斯度过了癌症治疗
I saw Lance - through his cancer treatment,
但是经历了这么多年的起起伏伏
but after all the years, the high, the lows,
我们之间没感情了
neither of us had anything left.
我们是和平分手的
I mean, it was all amicable.
你知道他来纽约做什么吗
Do you know what he was doing in town?
他在跟老搭档
He was shooting a film
布鲁克·哈蒙拍摄电影
with his old partner, Brock Harmon.
什么电影
What film?
《不倒硬汉》的最新续集
The next "Indestructibles" movie.
布鲁克执导
Brock's directing.
实际上  兰斯跟他住一起
In fact, Lance was staying with him.
如果出了什么问题  布鲁克会知道的
So if there was trouble, Brock would know about it.
上上上
Go, go, go!
真是太俗了
This is so cheesy.
她说的"俗"意思是"棒极了"
And by "Cheesy," she means "Amazing."
拜托  瞧瞧电影的奇迹
Come on. Behold the miracle of cinema.
真正的奇迹是那种女孩
The real miracle is how a girl like that
居然跟年龄大到足够
is hanging out with a bunch of guys
做她祖父的一群男人混在一起
who are old enough to be her grandfather.
她是塞拉菲纳  混合武术明星
That's Serafina, the mixed martial arts star.
她可以把那些人打得落花流水
She could beat all those guys to a pulp.
那人是谁
Who's that guy?
你不是逼我看了一部他出演的电影吗
Didn't you make me watch a movie with him in it?
洛夫·马格斯
Rolf Magnus.
他是北欧的健美运动员  门萨俱乐部的正式成员
He's a nordic bodybuilder, card-carrying member of Mensa.
我不知道  卡塞尔
I don't know, Castle.
也许我就喜欢老派的人
Maybe I just like the old-school guys, you know?
比如伊斯特伍德  布朗森  麦奎因
Like Eastwood, Bronson, McQueen --
真正的演员
Real actors.
那来看看克雷·比格斯吧
Well, then check out Clay Biggs.
以优异成绩在茱莉亚学院毕业
Graduated top of his class at Juilliard,
他跟布鲁克·哈蒙不一样
in contrast to Brock Harmon,
他首次亮相荧幕
who made his on-screen debut
-是作为AV男优...  -卡  卡
- as a porn star known as "Brock the --" Cut! That's a cut!
史蒂夫  给我找把能用的枪  要么就换份工作
Steve, get me something that works or get a new job.
谢谢
Thank you.
哈蒙先生
Mr. Harmon.
我是贝克特警探  这是卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett. This is Mr. Castle.
哈蒙先生  我是铁杆粉  铁杆粉
Mr. Harmon -- huge fan, huge fan.
我...  幸会幸会
I'm -- it's a hon-- honor to meet you.
是我的荣幸
The honor is mine.
我经常在厕所读你的书
I've passed many an hour in the john reading your books.
我们是为了兰斯·德鲁卡的事来的
We're here about Lance Delorca.
对我和我的家人来说是惨痛的一天
Ah. Sad day for me. And my family.
-来披上  亲爱的  -谢谢  宝贝
- Here you go, darling. - Oh, thanks, babe.
如果你是我的粉丝
Well, if you're a fan of mine,
那你肯定知道我妻子纳奥米·杜瓦雷
you know my wife, Naomi Duvray.
我希望你还知道她的珠宝首饰
And her jewelry line, too, I hope.
她刚发布了春季系列  很赞
She just launched a spring collection -- - Nice.
你在《铁胆硬汉》中扮演大佬的手下
You were just outstanding as El Jéfe's Henchwoman
太精彩了  那真是...
in "Hard Kill." That was -- ooh.
你真贴心
Oh, that is so sweet.
我的回旋踢很厉害  但我不是个很好的演员
I had a mean roundhouse kick, but I wasn't much of an actor.
这可没拦住我
Well, it never stopped me.
这是我儿子特雷
Oh, uh, this is my son, Trey.
幸会
Good to meet you.
哈蒙先生  我们能私下聊聊吗
Uh, Mr. Harmon, could we speak privately?
当然啦
Oh. Sure.
一个骨髓捐献者捐献的骨髓
Transplant from a bone-marrow donor,
让兰斯进入了缓解期  救了他的命
that's what put Lance in remission, saved his life.
他知道他得到了第二次机会
He knew he'd been given a second chance.
他戒酒了  洗心革面
He got sober, cleaned up his act.
所以我让他参演电影
That's why I gave him a part in the movie.
这本可成为他的东山再起之作
This could have been his big comeback.
我们听说他跟你住在一起
So, we understand that he was staying with you.
他看起来什么样子
How did he seem?
挺安静的  我甚至会说是守口如瓶
Quiet. Secretive, I'd even say.
兰斯一直都沉默寡言
Lance was always a man of few words,
但这次他说得更少
but even fewer this time out.
你知道他昨晚11点半在下东区
Any idea what he was doing on the Lower East Side
做什么吗
last night at 11:30?
我都不知道他来了市里
I didn't even know he was in town.
你说了他跟你住一起
You said he was staying with you.
是啊  兰斯上周拍完了
Right. Lance wrapped last week.
别人说他直接
I was told transportation took him
从片场去了机场
straight from the set to the airport.
好吧  我的警探需要跟司机谈谈
Okay, well, my detectives will need to speak with the driver,
还有兰斯认识的所有人
along with anyone else that Lance knew.
当然啦
Of course. Um...
到底发生了什么事  他怎么死的
What exactly happened? How did he die?
他是被绞喉勒死的
Um, he was strangled...with a garrote.
那对你有什么含义吗
Does that mean something to you?
你们知道兰斯是西情局的人对吧
You know Lance was CNI, right?
西班牙情报局
Spanish Intelligence.
-那跟他的谋杀有何关系  -关系大了去了
- What does that have to do with his murder? - Everything.
他是西情局的杀手  那是他的标志手法
He was a CNI assassin. That was his signature.
他用绞喉杀人
He killed people with a garrote.
所以别人用绞喉来杀他
Which is why it was used to kill him.
兰斯被谋杀了  因为他是西班牙版的杰森·伯恩
Lance was murdered because he's the Spanish Jason Bourne.
为什么  卡塞尔
Why, Castle?
因为穿着和服的B级动作片明星这样说吗
Because a "B" action-movie star in a kimono said so?
因为这合情合理
Because it makes sense.
兰斯借鉴自己作为无情的
Lance was drawing on his experience
西情局特工的经验  来扮演动作英雄
as a ruthless CNI operative to play action heroes.
但他神秘的过去找上了他
But his shadowy past caught up with him.
也许这是报复
Maybe it was revenge
某人因为他过去执行的暗杀
for a-a hit he did back in the day --
以彼之道  还施彼身
Kill him the way he killed.
卡塞尔  他30年前就离开了西情局
Castle, he left CNI 30 years ago.
为什么他的过去现在找上了他
Why would his past catch up to him now?
关于西情局的事  卡塞尔先生可能说对了
Mr. Castle might just be right about CNI.
我怎么对了
Aha. How -- how am I right?
埃斯波西托和莱恩去问讯片场的人了
Esposito and Ryan are off interviewing folks on the set.
但他们离开之前  他们有所发现
But before they left, they got onto something.
他们调出了兰斯的通话记录  他死的那天
They pulled Lance's phone records, and the day he died,
给西班牙的国际刑警组织打了电话
He made a phone call to interpol in Spain,
打给了恩里克·戈麦斯的办公室
to the office of one Enrique Gomez.
戈麦斯和西情局有什么关系
What does Gomez have to do with CNI?
根据他的简历  戈麦斯曾和兰斯·德鲁卡
According to his bio, Gomez used to work there
同时在西情局工作
at the same time Lance Delorca did.
兰斯联系了另一名前特工
So Lance reaches out to another ex-agent,
现在被绞喉杀害了
and he's killed with a garrote?
记住我的话
Mark my words...
这起案子会带领我们走进
...This case is gonna lead us into a labyrinthian world
欺骗  邪恶和国际间谍活动的迷宫世界
of deceit, villainy, and international espionage.
这比他的电影都还棒
This is better than one of his movies.
看过了拍摄现场  这是必须的
After what I saw, it'd have to be.
好  谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
最新情况
Update.
我联系了国际刑警组织  来追踪
I contacted interpol to track down
兰斯联系的那个人  恩里克·戈麦斯
that guy Lance called, Enrique Gomez.
原来戈麦斯现在在纽约
Well, it turns out gomez is here in New York
他来参加联合国会议
for a meeting at the U.N.
他昨晚11点半在哪
Where was he last night at 11:30?
从马德里飞来的夜间航班上
On a red-eye in from Madrid.
他今天一大早到的
He arrived early this morning,
所以他不是凶手
so he's not our killer.
但是国际刑警组织会让他过来接受问讯
But Interpol will send him over here for an interview.
他也许对谋杀案有自己的看法
He might have insight on the murder.
我跟西情局谈过了
Well, I talked to CNI
问了他们关于兰斯在任时的情况
to ask them about Lance's time there,
关于他涉及的任务
about missions that he was involved in,
他可能有的敌人  可他们总是含糊其辞
Enemies that he might have had, and they are stone-walling me.
西情局这样的情报机构
Intelligence agencies like CNI
肯定要避免透漏他们内部员工的信息
avoid disclosing information on their employees.
不过我在国务院还有点关系
But I do have contacts in the state department.
-我去问问  -好
- Let me just ask around. - Great.
我也在联系我在华盛顿的朋友了
I've reached out to my guys in Washington, as well.
贝克特  片场那边有发现
Hey, Beckett. I think we got something from that movie set.
我们问过送兰斯去机场的司机了
We talked to the driver who took Lance to the airport.
只是他根本没去机场
Only, that's not what he did.
兰斯其实在布鲁姆街
Lance asked the driver to drop him off
一个廉价旅馆下了车
at some seedy hotel on Broome Street.
他不希望任何人知道
And he didn't want anybody to know about it.
他付了司机100块
He paid the driver 100 bucks to lie
让他撒谎说把兰斯送到了肯尼迪机场
and say he dropped Lance off at JFK.
他去那旅馆干什么
Why would he go to this hotel?
这就是让人不解的地方了
Well, that's where it gets weird.
我们派去调查的人说
The unis we sent to canvass
兰斯在那租了个房间  租期一周
said that Lance had rented a room there for the past week.
用的名字是瑞克·克鲁斯
Under the name Rico Cruz,
他在《铁胆硬汉》中的角色名
his character from "Hard kill."
好吧
Um...Okay.
让他们查查旅馆的监控录像
Have unis check - for security video at the hotel,
咱们去他房间
And, uh, let's round up
收集他的个人物品
any of Lance's personal effects from his room.
好
Yeah.
-谢了  -不客气
- Thanks, l.T. - Yeah.
我不明白
I-I don't understand.
兰斯为什么要离开布鲁克·哈蒙在第五大道的寓所
Why would Lance leave Brock Harmon's fifth avenue digs
跑去住廉价旅馆
to go stay in a flophouse?
而且还不让任何人知道
And without telling anyone.
他肯定有什么打算
He's definitely up to something.
嗯
Yeah.
哇  《铁胆硬汉》的DVD
Hey! A "Hard kill" DVD.
看来兰斯是想回味从前啊
Looks like Lance was - trying to relive the old days.
"该克鲁斯控制局面了"
"Time to hit Cruz control."
你别说  也许这正是我需要的
You know, maybe that's what I need...
一句口头禅
a catchphrase.
"该主持正义了"
"Time to mete out justice."
"该...进监狱了"
"Time... for prison time."
呵呵  你继续  哥们儿
Yeah, you keep working on that, bro.
"该为杀人付出代价了"
"Time to pay the bill for doing the kill."
好吧  我又一想  还是不要了
Okay, on second thought, don't.
看  建筑草图
Hey. Building schematics?
这纸箱里还有一堆奇怪的东西
There's a bunch of weird stuff in this box.
烙铁  蓝色颜料
Soldering iron, blue craft paint,
麦克风  U盘  都是空壳
A microphone, a USB drive -- both empty cases.
感觉他是在组装什么东西
Looks like he was building something,
比如录音装置
Like a recording device.
还在上面加了贴纸吗
And then he added stickers to it?
贴纸  这是怎么回事
Stickers? - What the hell is that about?
不知道  但2和5对应的部分没有了
I don't know, but the "2" And "5" are missing.
特雷
"Trey."
肯定是指特雷·哈蒙  布鲁克·哈蒙的儿子
Hey, this must be Trey Harmon, Brock Harmon's kid.
兰斯给他打电话干什么
Why would Lance call him?
他让我给他推荐好的纽约夜店
He wanted to ask me - about the New York club scene.
这事我在行  我是夜店推手
That's my thing. I'm a club promoter.
但说实话  我回绝了他
But I kind of shut him down, to be honest.
为什么
Why is that?
得了癌症后  他不再酗酒了
After the cancer, he got sober.
我不可能帮他重拾旧瘾
No way I was gonna help him fall off the wagon
让他又开始玩乐
and start partying again.
你认得这个吗
Do you recognize this?
我觉得可能是个夜店的平面图
I think it might be the floor plan to a club.
我都没碰到你
I barely touched you.
不知道  我说不好这是什么
I don't know. I can't really tell what that is.
这是兰斯的吗
Did Lance have this?
对  我们觉得他应该不会是想开派对
Yeah, and we don't think that he wanted to party.
他有告诉你他为什么对夜店感兴趣吗
Did he explain to you why he was interested in clubs?
没有
Not really.
他只说有点事情他必须处理
He just said that there was something that he needed to take care of.
有点事情他必须处理
There was something he needed to take care of.
我有个想法
I have a theory.
很好  我现在正需要一个想法
Great, 'cause, right now, I could use one.
这是典型的动作电影桥段
It's a classic action-movie plot device.
兰斯  他做特工的日子已远去
Lance, his black-op days long behind him,
但他决定再进行最后一次任务
decides to go on one final mission
去征服他的宿敌
to vanquish his old nemesis.
会是谁
Which would be?
他的竞争对手  曾是他最好的朋友
Uh, it's a rival assassin who was once his best friend
但后来背叛了他
but then betrayed him.
或者是布洛菲尔德那样的超级大反派
Or, actually, uh, - a Blofeld-style supervillain
他杀了兰斯的妻子  随后消失了
who killed Lance's wife and then disappeared.
好吧  但凯特·金斯利还活着呢
Yeah, but Kat Kingsley is still alive.
不  兰斯的另一个妻子
No, Lance's other wife
在他以前那可悲又秘密的西情局生涯里娶的
from his tragic but secret CNI past.
我承认  任务和敌人的细节部分
Now, I admit I'm a little sketchy on the details
有点模糊
of the mission and the nemesis,
但总之  兰斯在着手一项任务
But bottom line is - Lance embarked on a mission.
但年事已高  他身手不如从前
The years had caught up with him. He had lost a step.
他被另一名特工干掉了
so he was dispatched by another operative
一个更年轻  更敏捷  也更致命的人
who was younger, quicker... and deadlier.
而且  很可能是女性
and...Possibly female.
托瑞检查了旅馆的监控录像
Tory screened that security-cam video
发现了这个
from the hotel and found this.
这是兰斯遇害当天
That's Lance leaving through the hotel lobby
经过旅馆大堂离开的画面
on his last day on earth.
10秒钟后  这个女人跟着他出去了
And 10 seconds later, this woman goes after him.
就是她  她就是特工
That's her. That's the operative.
她穿着深色外套
She's wearing a dark coat,
和离开犯罪现场的人一样
just like the person who left the crime scene.
她肯定从旅馆就尾随兰斯
She must have trailed Lance from the hotel,
进而杀了他
then moved in for the kill.
她是金发  但可能是假发
She's blond, but she might be wearing a wig.
看看她的太阳镜
Take a look at her sunglasses
还有她故意让面部角度避开摄像头的方式
and the way that she's angled her face away from the camera.
她不想被认出来
She didn't want to be I.D.'d.
她可能得逞了
She may have gotten her wish.
托瑞说镜头画面不足以进行面部识别
Tory said there's not enough here to run facial recognition.
她戴着耳环
You know, she's wearing an earring.
看看托瑞能不能从那个着手
See if Tory can do something with that.
恩里克·戈麦斯在来的路上
Enrique Gomez is on his way up.
也许他知道她是谁
Maybe he knows who she is.
不  我认不出她
Nope. I don't recognize her.
很遗憾兰斯去世了
I'm sad to learn of Lance's death.
你跟他是什么关系  戈麦斯先生
What was your relationship with him, Mr. Gomez?
我们年轻的时候很要好  近几年不行了
We were close as young men. Less so recently.
他死前给你打了电话  为什么
Yet, he called you just before he died? Why?
他需要一个保镖  一个他能信任的人
He needed a bodyguard, somebody he could trust.
而我认识这样的人
And I know such people.
可这种临时需求  他们都没空
But none of them were available on such short notice,
所以我没能帮他
so I couldn't help him.
兰斯为什么需要保镖
Why would Lance need a bodyguard?
他没说  我也没问
He didn't tell me. I didn't ask.
你觉得他有可能在执行最后一次任务吗
You think maybe he was going on one last mission?
或是他在西情局的过往找上了他
Or perhaps his CNI past was coming back to haunt him.
应该不太可能
Well, that would be rather unlikely.
兰斯并没有什么西情局的过去
You see, Lance didn't have a CNI past.
那怎么所有人都说他有呢
Why is everyone saying that he did?
我们是一起长大的
Well, we grew up together,
可加入西情局的人是我
but I was the one who went into CNI.
当兰斯来美国的时候
And when Lance came to America,
他求我把背景故事给他用
he asked me to use my backstory
这会使他看起来更神秘更有趣
to make himself more mysterious and interesting.
对不起
Uh, I'm s-- I'm so-- I'm sorry.
你是说兰斯·德鲁卡
Are you -- - are you saying Lance Delorca
以前不是西情局特工吗
wasn't a CNI operative?
在他进演艺圈之前
Before he started acting,
他在比利牛斯山放羊
he was a goat herder in the Pyrenees.
恩里克·戈麦斯的故事被核实了
So, Enrique Gomez's story checks out.
经他授权
And, with his authorization,
西情局证实了兰斯·德鲁卡不是他们的探员
CNI confirms that Lance Delorca was...never an agent.
我的英雄是个骗子  还是个放羊的
My hero was a liar... and a goat herder.
是的  先别管这个严重的个人背叛
Yes, well, despite - this deeply personal betrayal,
我们还有件谋杀案要破呢
we still have a murder to solve.
-怎么破  我们现在回到起点了  -未必
- How? We're back to square one. - Not necessarily.
不是还有个从单人间
I mean, there's still that mystery woman
跟踪兰斯的神秘女人吗
that followed Lance from the S.R.O.
她可能不再神秘了
She may not be a mystery anymore.
她也是放羊的吗
She a goat herder?
天呐
Oh, my god.
我没找到这对耳环的出处
I didn't get anywhere with the earrings.
实在太普通  但是我注意到了她的耳朵
They're too common, but that got me focused on her ear.
耳朵怎么了  看起来很正常
Okay. What about it? It looks normal.
是的  但是人耳识别技术
It is, but ear biometrics --
耳朵的大小  形状  结构
size, shape, configuration --
几乎和指纹一样具有唯一性
are almost as unique as fingerprints.
一整个领域都致力于研究这项课题
An entire field of study is devoted to the subject.
-耳生物学  -耳生物学
- Earology. - Earology.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
联调局研讨会
FBI seminar.
你用她的耳朵找出这个女人的身份了吗
So, you used her ear to identify this woman?
是的  通过分离这个耳朵
Yes, by isolating the ear
把它放进面部照片数据库中查找
and running it against the mug-shot database.
没有发现  然后我又在和兰斯·德鲁卡
When nothing popped, I ran it against photos of women
有关的那些女人的照片中查找
who had any connection with Lance Delorca.
电脑分析了上千张照片
The computer analyzed thousands of images
最后找到了相似度
and finally found a match
达99.2%的对象  就是这个女人
with a 99.2% probability that it's this woman.
是凯特·金斯利
That's Kat Kingsley.
兰斯是被他的准前妻杀害的吗
Lance was killed by his soon-to-be ex-wife?
我们听说凯特·金斯利在这里
Hey. So, we heard Kat Kingsley was here. Whoa!
穿这套衣服来接受审讯简直太性感了
And that is a sexy outfit for an interrogation.
这是她的戏服
It's her costume.
他们把她直接从片场带过来的
They took her - right from the set of her movie.
老兄  她可真是
Man, she is really --
-性感  -不显老啊
- Hot? - ...- Holding up well.
-什么电影  -是直接发行的影碟
- What's the movie? - It's direct-to-video.
她饰演的是女版的夺宝奇兵
She plays a female Indiana Jones.
她又演考古学家吗
She's an archaeologist again?
你们认为我求她给这个签名
So, do you think it would be weird
会不会有点怪
if I asked her to sign this?
什么时候签  去监狱的路上吗
When? On her way to jail?
这会对我意义重大的
It would mean so much to me.
她杀害兰斯的动机是什么
What would her motivation be for killing Lance?
看起来她的离婚过程比她说得
Well, it seems her divorce was a tad messier
要混乱得多
than she led us to believe.
你这次扮演的是什么角色  金斯利女士
So, what role are you playing now, Ms. Kingsley?
肯定不是悲伤寡妇
Not the grieving widow.
我必须回到片场
I need to get back to set,
不然他们会停止制作
or they're gonna shut down production
《夺宝奇兵之努比亚神庙》
on "Raiders of the Nubian temple."
是啊  可是你现在有个更严重的问题
Yeah, well, you've got bigger problems than that.
我跟兰斯的律师谈过了
So, I talked to Lance's lawyer,
他说你们的离婚过程一点也不平和
and he said that your divorce was anything but amicable.
我们是演员  都是充满激情的人
We're actors. We're passionate people.
有时候是会闹得激烈一些
Things got stormy at times.
因为你想得到马里布的房子
Because you wanted the Malibu house,
而他不想给你
and he didn't want to give it to you.
那套房子对我有情感价值
That home has sentimental value to me.
还有金钱价值
Along with monetary value.
我是说  过了二十年  它值
I mean, after 20 years, it's worth...
八百万美元
$8 million.
现在兰斯死了
And with Lance out of the picture,
这些就都是你的了
it was all yours.
你认为是我杀了我丈夫吗
You think I killed my husband?
你之前确实试图这么干过
You tried to before.
还记得那次事故吗
Remember the incident
你朝他开枪那次
where you discharged a firearm...at him?
我是在擦枪
I was cleaning it.
我分辨得出糟糕的表演
I know bad acting when I see it.
就是你  金斯利女士
This is you, Ms. Kingsley,
在兰斯被杀前数小时  跟踪了他
following Lance hours before he was killed.
我并不是在跟踪他
I was not following him.
他求我去见他
He asked me to meet with him.
他让你伪装了吗
And he told you to wear a disguise?
开枪事件后  我不能被别人看见跟他在一起
I couldn't be seen with him after the gun thing.
我们被告之要避免接触
We were told to avoid contact.
但是兰斯求我
But Lance begged me.
他需要现金  二十万
He needed cash -- $200,000.
他问你借钱吗
He asked you for a loan?
他的资产都因离婚官司而冻结了
His assets were all tied up with the divorce.
我继承了一些钱  他知道我可以拿到
I inherited some money. He knew I had access to it.
不是借钱
It wasn't a loan.
他把马里布房子的一半卖给了我
He sold me his half of the Malibu house.
你是说
Are you telling me
他用四百万万跟你换二十吗
that he traded you $4 million for $200,000?
我怎么能拒绝这样的交易呢
How could I pass up a deal like that?
我有本票  可以证实这件事
I have the promissory note to prove it.
他为什么需要钱
Why did he need the money?
他说他需要摆平一些事
He said he needed to set something right,
好像是说  他想像他扮演的角色一样英勇
that he wanted to live up to the characters he played, I think.
我没怎么仔细听
I wasn't really listening.
我只是想让他签字卖房
I just wanted him to sign over the house.
我说的都是实话
I'm just being honest.
如果你说的都是实话
Okay, fine, if you're being honest,
那为什么不告诉我...
then why don't you tell me this --
我们有目击者称
We have a witness
看到一个黑影从犯罪现场逃脱
that saw a dark figure fleeing the crime scene.
那是你吗
Was that you?
是的
Yes.
你能解释一下吗
Do you want to elaborate on that?
那晚兰斯用投币电话打给我
Lance called me that night from a pay phone.
他说他有麻烦了
I think he said he was in trouble
有人在追他
and that people were after him.
什么人
What people?
他没说
He didn't say.
不过他让我去接他
But he asked me to pick him up
就在那个放《铁胆硬汉》的电影院
at this theater playing "Hard kill,"
那样比较容易找到
that it would be easy to find.
他的声音听起来很绝望
H-he sounded so desperate.
但当我到达那里的时候
But when I got there...
他已经死了
...He was dead.
之前你为什么不告诉我们这些事
Why didn't you tell us this before?
我慌了
I panicked.
我正想重新开展我的事业
I'm trying to restart my career.
我知道这看起来就像我是凶手
I just knew how it might look.
那是因为这的确看起来就像你是凶手
Well, that's because - it's exactly how it does look.
在我看来不是
Well, not to me it doesn't.
我认为她不是凶手
I don't think she's our killer.
是啊  她就是个无辜的考古学家
Yeah, she's just an innocent archaeologist.
我的意见并未被她暴露的穿着左右
My opinion is not affected by her skimpy outfit.
我完全是以客观严谨
I'm speaking as an objective investigator,
不受个人感情影响的调查员的态度看待此事
someone who has set their personal feelings aside.
-还有你的海报呢  -谁告诉你的
- Along with your poster? - Who told you?
是莱恩吧  对吗
It was Ryan, wasn't it?
卡塞尔  凯特·金斯利承认去过现场
Castle, Kat Kingsley admitted to being at the crime scene.
在她根本没必要承认的情况下
Yeah, when she didn't have to.
她要是真有罪为什么要承认呢
Why admit to that if you're actually guilty?
以制造她无罪的假象
To make herself look not guilty.
她有动机
Look, she had motive.
但她的说法还是有真实的部分的
But parts of her story still check out --
她提到的本票
the promissory note,
她从银行提取的二十万美元
the withdrawal from her bank for $200,000.
兰斯说他需要这笔钱摆平一件事
Lance said he needed the money to set something right.
他想像他扮演的角色一样英勇
He needed to live up to his on-screen persona.
没错  但这说法来自犯罪嫌疑人
Yes, according to our murder suspect.
这是兰斯和他的骨髓捐献者的照片
So, here's Lance meeting his bone-marrow donor.
也许战胜白血病改变了他
Perhaps surviving leukemia changed him,
让他想做个更好的人
drove him to become a better man,
更像他演绎过的英雄那样的人
a man more like the hero he portrayed.
所以  当他在旅店登记时
That's why, when he registered at the hotel,
用了瑞克·克鲁兹  因为他进入了角色
he did so as Rico Cruz, because he became Rico Curz.
你在说什么啊
What does that even mean?
就是  哪怕曾经只是个牧羊人
That, despite being an ex-goat herder
完全没受过间谍训练
with no formal black-ops training,
兰斯却开始了一项任务
Lance took on a mission.
好吧  又回到最后的任务上来了
Oh, okay, so we're back to "One last mission" now.
否则他为什么需要构造图
Why else would he have the schematic
和窃听器呢
or the listening device?
还有为什么需要保镖呢
Or why would he need a bodyguard?
保护自己不受凯特·金斯利的伤害
To protect himself from Kat Kingsley.
不过她的说法站得住脚
Yeah, except for her story is still holding up.
她说接到的那通兰斯的电话
That call she says was from lance
是离影院六条街远的一个公共电话打来的
came from a pay phone six blocks from the movie theater.
好吧  追查是否有目击者
All right, canvass for witnesses
看到兰斯或者别人接近过那个电话
that saw Lance or anyone else by that pay phone.
如果像凯特说的   他真的有麻烦了
And if he was in trouble, as Kat said,
那就查查哪来的麻烦
then let's find out where he was coming from.
马上去查
We'll get into it,
但可能要明早才能有消息了
but we might not have anything till the morning.
好
Okay.
你把海报的事告诉她了
You told her about the poster.
我不知道这是个秘密啊
I didn't know it was a se--
我不知道
I don't know.
也许是他说的方式
Maybe it's the way that he said it
刺激到了我吧
that struck a nerve.
察言观色也不是他的特长啊
Well, tact isn't exactly the man's middle name.
好吧  但这是我的家  不是卡塞尔的
Okay, but it's my place, you know? It's not Castle's.
谁在乎他喜不喜欢
Who cares if he never liked it?
我也不知道自己为什么这么郁闷
I mean, I don't know why I got so upset.
因为对他这里不过是地板吱吱作响的破房子
Because, to him, this is just an apartment with creaky floors.
但对你  这里是你重新开始生活的地方
But to you, this is where you rebuilt your life,
你在这侦破你母亲的案子
where you solved your mother's murder,
坠入爱河
where you fell in love.
那
Well...
敬最棒的公寓
To the best apartment ever.
找到目击者  发现重要线索
So, we struck gold on that canvass.
有人看到兰斯用那台电话了
Someone saw Lance using the pay phone?
没  但之前有人看到他
No, but they saw him before that
从一条小巷慌张地跑出来
running like hell from an alley.
指引我们在附近找到这份监控录像
Which leads us to this security-cam video right here.
不亲眼见到你绝对不会相信
You got to see it to believe it.
这四个人围住了兰斯
These four guys have got Lance cornered.
糟糕了
Oh, this can't be good.
这些人是谁啊
Who are those guys?
不知道  但不禁让人去想
I don't know, but makes you wonder
兰斯干了什么  招惹到他们
what Lance did to have them come after him.
上了年纪的兰斯·德鲁卡面对四个暴徒
Four thugs against a-an aging Lance Delorca?
我不敢看了
I don't know that I can watch.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?!
兰斯刚刚的举动
What Lance just did...
简直就是他影片里的情节
that belongs in one of his movies.
他解决了他们
He annihilated them.
但没过多久
Yeah, but not for long.
半小时后  他就被别人解决了
Half an hour later, someone annihilated him.
好吧
Ah, well, right.
至少这解释了电话的事
But at least this explains the phone call.
兰斯打给凯特·金斯利
When Lance called Kat Kingsley
说我有麻烦了  有人在追我
and said, "I'm in trouble and people are after me,"
指的就是这件事
this is what he was talking about.
不管这些人是谁  肯定又找上了他
And whoever these guys are, they must have caught up to him.
只要找到他们  就能找到凶手
We find these guys, we'll find our killer.
从监控录像没法确认他们的身份
We can't I.D. any of these guys off of the surveillance video.
托瑞说图像清晰度太低
Tory says that the image quality is too poor
面部识别和耳纹识别都没法做
to run facial recognition, or ear recognition.
关键在于弄清楚兰斯在去
The key is finding out what happened to Lance
那条小巷之前发生了什么
before he wound up in that alley --
一件需要二十万美元和窃听器办的事
Something that required $200,000 and a listening device.
不管他对付的是谁
But whomever he went up against
就是这个人派来的打手
sent those four sides of beef after him.
看过这些人被痛扁
And, after seeing the ass-whupping they got,
我去查了周围的医院
I checked nearby hospitals.
在那个时间段  有人往这附近
Turns out that an ambulance was called to that area
叫了救护车
during our time window.
载着一个体格魁梧的家伙去了急诊
They brought in a heavy-set dude to the E.R.
昏迷不醒  带有瘀伤  下巴可能骨折了
He was unconscious, bruised, and had a possible broken jaw.
-好吧  去找他聊聊  -不行
- All right, let's go talk to him. - We can't.
他醒来后就自己办了出院手续
He woke up and checked himself out of the E.R.
他们都没来得及记下名字
before they could even get his name.
那医院有监控吗
Does the hospital have cameras?
很高兴你问了
I'm glad you asked that.
这人绝对就是录像中的其中一个
This guy definitely looks like one of the guys from the video.
等等  我见过这个人
Wait a second. I know that guy.
在拍摄现场  他当时一身阿富汗打扮
Yeah, from the film set. He was dressed in Afghan Garb.
布鲁克·哈蒙都没怎么碰到他的脸
Brock Harmon barely tapped him in the face,
他就大喊起来
and he screamed like a baby.
也许是因为他下巴骨折了
Perhaps because he has a broken jaw.
片场助手说他叫欧尼斯特·豪
A.D. says his name is Ernest Howe.
扮演的是恐怖组织士兵12号
And he's playing isis militant number 12.
演到头了
Not for long.
你知道现在是什么时候吗  莱恩时刻
You know what time it is? It's Ryan time.
拜托  够了
Please. Just stop.
我是莱恩  我痛恨谎言
My name's Ryan, and I hate lyin'.
欧尼斯特·豪  纽约警察
Ernest Howe. NYPD.
我们来跟你谈谈兰斯·德鲁卡
We're here to talk to you about Lance Delorca.
他死了真是遗憾
Yeah, it's a bummer that he died.
你的下巴怎么了  欧尼斯特
Got a little problem with your jaw there, Ernest?
轻微颞下颌紊乱
Little TMJ.
你确定不是因为那天晚上
You sure it's not - from that little altercation
你参与的某场斗殴吗
you got into the other night?
我不想再惹上什么麻烦了
Look, I don't want any more trouble.
你有麻烦了  莱恩式麻烦
Well, you got trouble -- Ryan trouble.
-没听说过  -有监控拍到了你
- I don't know what that means. - We have you on video.
你和其他三个打手袭击了兰斯
You and those three mooks attacked Lance,
受伤的却是你们
and he put the hurt on all of you.
不过显然不重  因为你们其中有人杀了他
But not enough hurt, because one of them killed him.
既然你去了急诊  说明这人不是你
Judging by your little trip to the E.R., it wasn't you.
所以你最好告诉我们你同伙的名字
So why don't you give us the name of your buddies, Ernest,
-还有下命令的人  -你们搞错了
- and whoever put them up to this. - You got it all wrong.
我的伤就是那些人打的
Those guys did this to me.
我和兰斯是一伙的  他让我当他的保镖
I was on Lance's side. He hired me to be his bodyguard.
为什么兰斯需要保镖
Why would Lance need a bodyguard?
他在漂移俱乐部和人碰面  他想找后援
He had a meeting at Club Drift. He wanted backup.
他带了个手提箱  我觉得里面装了钱
He brought a briefcase. I think it had money on it.
他在那和谁碰面  带钱干什么
Who did he meet there and what was the money for?
我不知道  他们让我在楼下等
I don't know. They made me wait downstairs.
但是会面很快就结束了
But the meeting ended quick.
突然四个保安推搡着让我们赶紧走
All of a sudden, four security dudes hustled us out
说兰斯戴了窃听器
and accused Lance of wearing a wire.
窃听器  他为什么要戴窃听器
A wire? - Why would he be wearing a wire?
我还没来得及问
Well, I didn't exactly get a chance to ask.
我最后记得的就是
The last thing I remember was
一个家伙用脚踹了我的脸
a guy's foot flying across my face.
可能兰斯的确戴了窃听器
Maybe Lance was wearing a wire.
这样就能解释那个麦克风和闪存盘
That would explain the microphone and the usb drive.
不  欧尼斯特说保安并没有找到窃听器
Nah, Ernest said that security didn't find a wire,
而且兰斯的身上也没有
and there wasn't one on Lance's body.
但我们假设一下他确实戴了窃听器
But let's say he was all wired up
并且拿了一箱子钱
with a briefcase of money.
他到底要干什么呢
What the hell was he doing?
好像兰斯
It's like Lance is running
在尝试一个计划不完善的诱捕行动
some kind of half-assed sting operation.
说不定他就是  我和缉毒队谈过了
Maybe he was. I spoke to Narcotics.
兰斯去的那家俱乐部是贩卖毒品的窝点
The club that Lance went to is a major hub for drug sales,
卡塞尔  那俱乐部是你熟悉的人经营的
run by a guy that you're familiar with, Castle.
这是
Is...
这是那个亨利·艾伦·布斯吗
Is that Henry Allen Boothe?
《铁胆硬汉》里的大佬
El Jéfe from "Hard Kill"?
他就是靠演一个毒贩子而火起来的
He made a career - out of playing drug dealers
之后他不再演戏
and then he quit acting.
直接做起了毒枭
And then he began living the part.
显然  他花了太多时间和毒贩在一起
Apparently, he spent so much time with drug dealers
研究角色以致他自己成为了一名毒贩
researching his roles that he actually became one.
不过缉毒队一直没法对他立案
Narcotics hasn't been able to make a case against him, though.
这就像《铁血硬汉》里的剧情一样
This is just like "Hard kill,"
瑞克·克鲁斯除掉了大佬
Where Rico Cruz took down El Jéfe.
只不过现在是一个演员要除掉另一个演员
Only, now it's one actor taking on the other actor,
可这另一个演员恰好是一毒贩
but the other actor actually happens to be a drug dealer.
但是  为什么兰斯要这么做呢
But, a-again, why would Lance do this?
为什么他要去追查布斯呢
Why would he go after Boothe?
我不知道  但是这也太戏剧化了
I don't know, but it's so meta!
我们得和大佬谈谈
We should really talk to El Jéfe.
相信我  我们会的
Oh, believe me -- we will.
是的  我和兰斯见过
Yeah, sure, I met with Lance.
你们谈了些什么呢
What about?
怀念旧时光
Mm, old times.
他想和我喝一杯  重温过去的光辉岁月
He wanted to share a drink, relive the glory days.
这么突然吗
Just out of the blue?
为什么不呢  《铁血硬汉》让我俩收获颇丰
Why not? "Hard Kill" - did a solid for both of us.
即使过了这么多年
Even after all these years, not a day goes by
每天都会有些中年人看到我
where some middle-aged dude doesn't see me
大喊"大佬"
and shout, "El Jéfe!"
我想我也没什么好抱怨的
I suppose I shouldn't complain.
那个角色让我拥有了这家俱乐部
That role bought me this club.
布斯先生  据我们所知它给你的可不止这个
We hear that it did more than that, Mr. Boothe.
电影里的毒贩成了真的毒贩  是吗
So the movie drug dealer becomes a drug dealer, huh?
如果这是真的  是个好故事
It'd be a good story if it were true.
话虽这么说  我也没去管它
That being said, I don't discourage it.
毕竟一个虚构的好故事也能给人带来名声
A good fiction can do wonders for one's reputation.
据我所知  任何一个虚构的好故事
I've learned that every good fiction
都包含了一定的真实性
contains a kernel of truth.
兰斯带来的那个手提箱哪儿去了
What happened to the briefcase that Lance brought
装有二十万现金的箱子
to the meeting, the one with $200,000 in it?
兰斯没带手提箱
Lance had no briefcase.
我想你的手下也没有把他赶出去
And I suppose your guys didn't chase him out of here
并且袭击了他  对吧
and then attack him?
我想不起来了
Doesn't ring a bell.
-我们有录像  -不是我的人
- We have a video. - Not of my guys.
你们可以来查
You're welcome to check.
我怀疑你能在这找到他们
I doubt you'll find any of them here.
关于你下个问题
And since your next question will be,
我那晚在哪里  我来帮你省点力气
"Where was I that night?" I'll save you the oxygen.
楼下有20个人
There are about 20 people downstairs
可以为我作证  在兰斯离开后
who can attest that I never left the building
我没有离开过这栋楼
after Lance left.
我没有杀他
I didn't kill him.
好的  谢谢你抽出时间
Okay. Thanks for your time.
谢谢你抽出时间
"Thanks for your time"?
贝克特  他在撒谎  那些钱
Beckett, he was lying about the money,
他们的碰面  全是谎言
about the meeting, about everything.
他当然是在撒谎
Of course he was lying.
你怎么不强硬一点  不去查他的不在场证明吗
So why didn't you push harder? Why didn't we check his alibi?
因为没有必要
Because we didn't need to.
从什么时候开始的事
Since when?
从我知道5和2的意思开始
Since I figured out what the numbers 5 and 2 meant.
贴纸上缺失的数字
The missing numbers from the sticker sheet.
数字52就在布斯收藏的赛车模型上
The number 52 was on a slot car in Boothe's collection --
确切的说是一辆蓝色的谢尔比眼镜蛇
A blue shelby cobra to be exact.
那就是兰斯制作的东西
That's what Lance was building.
他把一个窃听装置
He put a listening device
放进了一个布斯收藏车的复制品里
inside a replica of one of boothe's cars.
他肯定是在他们碰面的时候换掉了车
He must have switched them out when they had that meeting.
也就是说那辆车记录了在那发生的一切
Which means that car was recording everything
包括兰斯在那的原因
that happened in that office, including why Lance was there.
还有为什么布斯要杀掉他
And why Boothe had him killed.
我们得拿到那个赛车模型
We need to get that slot car.
会的  我们只需要先拿到搜查令
We will. We just need a warrant first.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你是说你拿不到搜查令
You're telling me - you can't get a search warrant,
即使那个狗娘养的布斯就是凶手
even though that son of a bitch Boothe is behind this?
除非我们能提供证据
Not unless we can provide evidence
证明布斯和兰斯的死有关
that ties Boothe to Lance's death.
而现在  我们甚至不能证明他们见过面
And, right now, we can't even prove that the two of them met.
听着  哈蒙先生
Look, Mr. Harmon,
我们希望你能帮助我们
we were hoping that you could help us with this.
兰斯跟你说过他要去那家俱乐部
Did Lance tell you that he was going to the club,
他要去见布斯吗
that he was gonna talk to Boothe?
关于布斯  那家俱乐部
Lance never said a word to me
兰斯一个字都没跟我说过
about Boothe or the club, nothing.
该死  我还以为他在洛杉矶
Hell, I thought he was in L.A.
我也希望能够帮到你们
I wish I could help you.
你知道吗
Well, you know what?
我们会继续找袭击兰斯的那群人
We'll keep looking for the men that attacked Lance.
我们不会放弃的
We're not giving up.
卡塞尔
Castle.
兰斯怎么知道在赛车模型上装窃听器
How did Lance know to bug a slot car?
布斯和他的收藏
Boothe and his collection
被刊登在了一本赛车杂志上
were featured in slotzone magazine.
你真觉得能证明谁杀害兰斯的证据
So you really think the proof of who killed Lance
就在那辆小蓝色谢尔比眼镜蛇里吗
is sitting in that little blue shelby cobra?
没拿到搜查令  说什么都没有用
Well, doesn't matter if we can't get a warrant.
真可惜这时瑞克·克鲁斯不在
Too bad Rico Cruz isn't around.
我敢肯定他能够找到办法
I bet he'd find a way, right?
你是个铁杆粉  对吧
So, you, uh -- - you're a pretty big fan, huh?
《铁血硬汉》吗
Of "Hard kill"?
不  我只是普通粉  一般粉
No, I was an average, ordinary fan.
我可没有《铁血硬汉》版睡衣
Not like I had the "Hard Kill" Pajamas.
我和那帮家伙
Say, the, uh, gang and I
今晚会去喝酒
are going out for drinks later tonight.
你愿意和我们一起去吗
How would you like to come with us?
卡塞尔
Castle?
你肯定猜不到刚才发生了什么
You are never gonna believe what just happened.
布鲁克邀我和"不倒硬汉"们喝一杯
Brock invited me to go drinking with The Indestructibles.
我和他们一起
Me with them.
那你肯定拒绝了他们对吧
But you told him that you couldn't
因为你现在还有案子要办
because you're in the middle of a case, right?
没  什么  不  我...
No. What? No. I just --
什么...我就是想...
What -- isn't it okay if I --
卡塞尔  你不会真的以为我会阻止
Castle, you really think that I could stand between
你实现你的儿时梦想吧
you and your boyhood dream?
你才是我的儿时梦想
You are my boyhood dream.
你还有和"不倒硬汉"们一起喝酒
Well, you and drinking with The Indestructibles.
你真的不用把这些说出来
You don't always have to keep talking.
-也对  -去吧
- Right. - Yeah.
那我去...那我去了
I'm gonna -- I'm gonna go.
我都不知道我该穿什么了
I don't know what I'm gonna wear.
我得赶紧准备了
I got to get ready.
好了
All right.
Okay.
你们...根本不知道我有多兴奋...
Well, you guys -- you have no idea how excited I am to...
你们是直接从片场过来的吗
You guys just come from set or something?
小伙子  我们是地狱来客
Son, we came straight from hell.
出发吧
Let's roll.
那...究竟是怎么回事
So, um... What's going on?
没搜查令并不能阻止我们
No warrant is gonna stop us
拿到将杀死兰斯凶手定罪的证据
from getting our hands on evidence to put away Lance's killer.
有人杀死了我们中的一员
Somebody takes out one of our own,
我们一定会替他报仇的
we take him out.
伙计们
Oh, guys, hey,
听着  如果你们的计划是到那个俱乐部
listen, if your plan is to go to the club
偷走那个模型车
and steal that slot car,
那可不行  那会...那会玷污证据的
N-no. That would -- that would taint the evidence.
实际上  我们可以强迫检察官接受这个证物
Actually, we can compel the D.A. to consider it
因为那车本来就是被害人兰斯的
since the car technically belonged to the victim, Lance.
你真的是天才啊
You really are a genius, aren't you?
另外  我们都不是执法人员
Also, none of us is an agent of the law.
这也是我们挑选你的原因
It's one of the reasons I chose you.
还因为你去过布斯的办公室
And because you have been in Boothe's office.
得靠你帮我们找到那辆模型车
You're gonna help us find that slot car.
不  不  不不不
No. No. No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
伙计们  我老婆是个警察
Guys, my wife is a cop.
如果我这么做了  她会杀了我的
If I do this, she'll kill me.
"我的老婆会杀了我的"
"Oh, my wife's gonna kill me."
这像是瑞克·克鲁斯说的话吗
Is that what Rico Cruz would say?
不像
No.
-如果被抓到怎么办  -不会被抓到的
- But what if we get caught? - We're not gonna get caught.
我们是"不倒硬汉"
We're The Indestructibles.
打起精神  伙计们  好戏要上场了
Tense up, guys. It's showtime.
计划很简单
The plan is simple.
一进俱乐部  塞拉菲纳  克雷  洛夫
Once we get to the club, Serafina, Clay, Rolf,
你们就从正门进去然后各就各位
go in through the main entrance and take your positions.
塞拉菲纳  找到后门之后通知我们
Serafina, alert us when you have eyes on the rear door.
老鹰回巢了
Falcon is in the nest.
克雷  你和洛夫想办法把布斯骗到下面吧台来
Clay, you and Rolf create a diversion to draw Boothe down to the bar.
小伙计  小伙计
Young fella, young fella.
我们要来整瓶的  你这儿有那个"天使"吗
We're doing bottle service. You got some of that Angel?
就是那个香槟
You know, the champagne?
当然  能给我你的信用卡吗  大块头
Sure do. Just gonna need your credit card, Mr. Biggs.
如果你知道我们是谁
If you know who we are,
就该知道我们从里根当总统那时起就不付酒钱了
then you know we haven't paid for a drink since Reagan.
先生  "天使"可是一千一瓶
Sir, Angel is a grand a bottle.
你也明白的
You understand.
小子  我们是来缅怀逝去战友的
Son, we're here to toast a fallen comrade.
难道过气的布斯太小气  不愿表示悼念吗
That has-been Boothe too cheap to pay respects?
-布斯先生  -什么事
- Mr. Boothe? - Yeah?
吧台这儿有几个你的老朋友
Got some old friends of yours at the bar.
你应该下来看看
You should come down.
好的  我下来了
All right, I'm coming down.
一旦大佬下楼  塞拉菲纳
Once El Jéfe's on the move, Serafina,
你就把后门打开
you'll unlock the villa gates.
土拨鼠出现了
Prairie dog is on the plain.
卡塞尔和我就直奔目标
And Castle and I will go for the goods...
"铁胆硬汉"风格
"Hard Kill" Style.
好了
Okay.
总是先检查下
Always check.
在哪儿  在哪儿
Okay, okay.
我得走了  很高兴见到你  伙计
I got to get going. Great seeing you, man.
你要去哪里
Where you going?
别走了  一起来喝一杯吧
Hey, hey. You know what? Come on. Hang out.
拜托  伙计  喝一杯
Come on, man. Hang out.
你们尽管喝  都算我的
Anything you want on me. Enjoy.
终止  终止
Abort. Abort.
土拨鼠拿了回旋镖
Prairie dog pulled a boomerang.
-我找到了  -布斯正在上楼
- I got it! - Boothe's on his way back up.
-什么  不  -是的
- What?! No. - Yeah.
土拨鼠回洞了
The prairie dog is in the burrow.
土拨鼠会把我们杀了的
Prairie dog's gonna kill us.
我们会被土拨鼠杀了的
We're gonna be killed by a prairie dog!
简直就像在出演自己的动作片
I'm starring in my own action movie.
这是最美妙的夜晚
This is the best night ever.
快走
Go!
你是想说
You're telling me that
这是一位"热心的公民"交给你的
this was handed to you by a "concerned citizen"?
是的
Yes.
卡塞尔
Castle?
这大概就是那种
This is probably one of those times
我该住嘴的时候
where I shouldn't keep talking,
这是为了我们好
for both our sakes.
接下来你将听到的录音
The recording you are about to hear
会提供无可争议的证据证明
will provide incontrovertible proof
亨利·艾伦·布斯是谋害兰斯·德鲁卡的幕后主谋
that Henry Allen Boothe ordered the murder of Lance Delorca.
没有声音
Sound's not working.
稍等一下  这是...
Hang on a second. This was...
耳机  你为什么不让我也听听
Headphones? Aren't you gonna let me hear it?
作为你半违法行为的奖励吗
And reward you for your semi-illegal behavior?
我看还是算了
I think not.
我...
I...
好吧  我来把它弄到功放上
Fine, I'll put it on speaker.
不是吧
Seriously?
要不是因为我  我们根本不会...
Because if it wasn't for me, we wouldn't even...
怎么了
What?
兰斯刚走进布斯的办公室
Lance just walked in to Boothe's office.
他们在互相寒暄
They're exchanging pleasantries.
现在要开始说正事了
And they're getting down to business.
我的天
Oh, my god.
怎么了
What is it?
-我的天  -他到底在说什么
- Oh, my god. - What is he saying?
求你了快告诉我他们在说什么
Please, just tell me what they're saying.
这和我想的完全不同
This is so not what I expected.
我的天
Oh, my god.
这是怎么回事
So, what's this about?
特雷  你有多了解亨利·艾伦·布斯
Trey, how well do you know Henry Allen Boothe?
如果有人拥有一家俱乐部
Well, if someone owns a club,
那我的职责就是去认识他
it's my job to know them.
我是通过我父亲认识的
I met him through my dad.
他们一起拍过一些电影
They did a few movies together.
事实上  布斯给了你些本钱
In fact, Boothe invested some seed money
这样你才能成为夜店推手
so you could become a club promoter.
作为一名推手
Then, as a promoter,
你就能随意进出全市所有俱乐部
you had access to all the clubs in the city.
布斯利用这一点
Boothe used that access
在那些俱乐部里贩卖毒品
to sell drugs in those clubs,
至少缉毒队是这么告诉我们的
or so we're told by narcotics.
你似乎并不否认这个  特雷
I don't hear you denying this, Trey.
我一开始并不知道毒品的事情
I didn't know about the drugs at first,
等我知道以后  已经太晚了
and once I did, it was too late.
-他控制了我  -让我猜猜
- He owned me. - Let me guess.
布斯说你可以一次性买断
Boothe said you could buy him out,
但他知道你付不起那个价
but at a price he knew you could never afford.
他开价多少  二十万吗
What was it? $200,000?
你没跟你的父母讲这件事  对吧
You didn't tell your parents about any of this, did you?
我想自己想办法
I wanted to make my own way,
而不是求助于布鲁克·哈蒙
not have Brock Harmon come to the rescue.
但被兰斯知道了
But Lance found out.
他想买断布斯  赎回你的自由
He tried to buy out Boothe, pay your ransom,
就像瑞克·克鲁斯在《铁胆硬汉》里那样
just like Rico Cruz did in "Hard Kill".
我求他不要这么做
Yeah, and I begged him not to.
这又不是在演电影
This wasn't some movie.
我知道布斯是不会放过我的
I knew that Boothe wasn't gonna let me go,
兰斯也无法拿着一带钱跑去
and Lance couldn't just walk in there with a bag of money
就把事情解决了
and fix things.
但是  突然间  他想当英雄
But, suddenly, he wanted to be a hero.
我跟他说  他会把我们俩都害死的
I told him he was gonna get us both killed.
但他为了救你只赔上了自己的性命
But he only got himself killed trying to save you.
我们录下了布斯当晚说的话
We have an audio recording of Boothe from that night.
怎么录到的
How?
兰斯在他办公室里装了窃听器
Lance bugged his office.
布斯把兰斯赶出自己的办公室后
After Boothe kicked Lance out of his office,
派了自己的手下去干掉他
he sent his men after him.
兰斯像动作片英雄一样海扁了他们
Lance gave them a beatdown worthy of an action hero.
这时  布斯打了一通电话
That's when Boothe made this phone call.
特雷  你哥们兰斯来过
Trey, your pal Lance was here.
我想你知道原因
I think you know why.
他现在在那家
He's on the run somewhere
上映《铁胆硬汉》的剧院附近
near that theater playing "Hard Kill".
接下来交给你了
He's your problem now.
你必须收拾他作为赔罪
You need to take care of him to make this right,
不然我就收拾你
or I'll take care of you.
就这样  特雷  去吧
You do that, Trey. Get it...done.
你怕布斯怕得要命  所以你杀了兰斯
You were so afraid of Boothe that you killed Lance
来保自己的小命
in order to save your own skin.
我才不会这么做呢
I would never do that.
听起来你正是这么做的
It sounds like that's exactly what you did do.
你挂电话之后呢
Now, what happened after you hung up?
我吓傻了
I freaked.
我打电话给我母亲  把事情都告诉她了
I called my mom, told her everything,
来龙去脉都说了
the whole story.
她叫我躲一躲  她会联系律师
She said to lay low, that she'd call a lawyer.
然后第二天早上  兰斯就死了
And then, the next morning, Lance was dead.
我以为他是被布斯的人干掉了
I figured Boothe's guys got to him.
我整晚都在我办公室
Look, I was at my office all night.
我睡在那了  清洁人员看到我了
I slept there. The cleaning crew saw me.
我发誓我没杀兰斯
I swear to you I did not kill Lance.
我也不知道是谁干的
And I don't know who did.
告诉我  特雷
Tell me, Trey --
兰斯为什么要费这么大劲帮你呢
why would Lance go through all this trouble to help you?
我不知道
I don't know.
他只是说癌症让他醒悟了
He just said that the cancer really woke him up
他说等这一切结束了
and that, uh, after all this was over,
他要告诉我一些事
there were some things that he wanted to tell me.
清洁人员证实了特雷的说法
So, the cleaning crew confirmed Trey's story.
他不是凶手
He is not our killer.
也许是布斯的一个手下干的
Maybe it was one of Boothe's men.
我们还没排除他们的嫌疑
We still haven't ruled them out.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我发现了一件很有意思的事
I just found something very interesting.
凶手的身份
The identity of the killer.
不  不是
No, not that.
你们记得特雷说癌症让兰斯醒悟了
You know how Trey said that Lance's cancer woke him up?
我刚跟他的医生谈完
Well, I just spoke to his doctor.
兰斯拿到骨髓捐赠者名字时  他想感谢人家
When Lance got the name of his bone-marrow donor
他发现和他骨髓配型结果非常相近的
to thank him, he found out there was a second donor
还有另一位捐赠者
who was a very close match.
看看那个名字
Take a look at that name.
你们把特雷放了吗
Have you released Trey yet?
他跟这件事没关系
He had nothing to do with this.
实际上  所有这一切都跟特雷有关
Actually, Trey has everything to do with this.
我好像不太明白
I'm not sure I understand.
当兰斯需要骨髓移植
When Lance needed a bone-marrow transplant,
特雷也捐献了样本看自己是否匹配
Trey gave a sample to see if he could donate.
我们都给了  那是我们最起码应该做的
We all did. It was the least we could do.
只不过特雷的样本几乎完全匹配
Except Trey's sample was nearly a match.
兰斯肯定也有所怀疑
Lance must have had his suspicions
因为他用那个样本做了亲子鉴定
because he ran a paternity test on that sample.
特雷是他的儿子
Trey was his son.
不
No.
特雷应该是在
He would have been conceived
拍《铁胆硬汉》时怀上的
during the filming of "Hard Kill",
这还真是麻烦
which is inconvenient,
因为那时你已经嫁给了布鲁克
since you were already married to Brock.
我们跟你的门房纳奥米谈过
We spoke to your doorman, Naomi.
他说兰斯被杀当晚
He said that you didn't come home
你过了后半夜才回家
until well after midnight the night that Lance was killed,
你去哪了
so where were you?
我没杀兰斯  如果你是这个意思的话
I didn't kill Lance, if that's what you're suggesting.
你完全有这个本事
You're more than capable of it.
你不仅回旋踢很厉害
You don't just have a mean roundhouse.
你还有两个黑带
You hold two black belts.
够了  你们该走了
Okay, you need to leave.
我们找到了凶器
We matched the wire.
你在你珠宝品牌中使用的串线
The wire that you use for your jewelry line,
跟你现在戴的项链一样
like the necklace that you're wearing right now --
跟我们的凶器完全吻合
it's an exact match to our murder weapon.
特雷跟你说
Trey told you
兰斯有重要的事情要告诉他
that Lance had something important to tell him.
你知道真相即将暴露
You knew the truth would come out.
兰斯会毁掉一切的
Lance would have destroyed everything --
我的婚姻  我的家庭
my marriage, my family,
我花了近30年时间建立的一切
everything that I spent almost 30 years trying to build.
我不能让他这么做
I couldn't let him do that.
怎么回事
What's going on?
告诉你们一件事  亨利·艾伦·布斯
You might be interested to know that Henry Allen Boothe
已被缉毒科逮捕了
was just arrested by narcotics.
他们不是无法立案吗
I thought they couldn't make a case.
之前是不行  可是当特雷知道
Well, they couldn't, but when Trey learned the truth
兰斯这么做的真相后
about why Lance really did all this,
他站了出来  决定要指证布斯
he stepped up and decided to testify against Boothe.
干得好  贝克特警探  卡塞尔先生
So good work, Detective Beckett, Mr. Castle.
别工作得太晚
Don't stay late.
剩下的文书工作可以明早再弄
You can finish the paperwork in the morning.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
看来兰斯最后还是成功战胜了他的宿敌
Looks like Lance managed to vanquish his nemesis after all.
这作为结局也不错了
An ending worthy of one of his movies.
你知道吗
You know...
也许我们今晚该看看《铁胆硬汉》
maybe we should watch "Hard Kill" tonight...
以表悼念
in his honor.
我也想这么说呢
I was just gonna suggest the exact same thing.
咱们现在想法都一样了
We're starting to think alike now.
这太吓人了  好吧  你去准备电影吧
That is horrifying. Okay, uh, go cue up the movie.
开瓶红酒  我一会就到家
Open up a bottle of wine. I'll be home in a bit.
我得先去个地方
I've just got a stop to make first.
如果咱俩想得真一样的话
Well, if I'm thinking what you're thinking --
你是去买一套性感的考古学家服饰
and it's to pick up a sexy archaeologist costume --
别担心
don't worry.
我已经买好鞭子了
I've already got the whip.
谢谢
Thank you.